olympus-ims.com 2018-12-29

# Privacy Notice | Olympus IMS

This page describes the rules in which personal information is handled in the Website of Olympus Corporation, displayed at the URL www.olympus-ims.com ("Website"). If you reside in the European Union, please click this link for the Privacy Notice that is applicable to you. 

At Olympus Corporation (hereinafter referred to as "we/us/our/Olympus”), we are deeply aware of the importance of your personal information.  We handle and thoroughly protect all personal information that you provide to us according to the Olympus Personal Information Protection Policy.  For information on the Olympus Group's policy on handling personal information, please see the Olympus Personal Information Protection Policy.

 **1\. Purpose of Obtaining Personal Information**

Unless your prior consent is given or unless permitted by law, Olympus will use the personal information provided by you for the purposes listed below or for purposes that are obvious given the state in which your information was acquired:

\- To respond to your inquiries or your requests  
\- For market research concerning Olympus' business, preparation of statistics and product development

Olympus will obtain your prior consent in the event that Olympus intends to use your personal information for purposes other than the above.

In order to achieve the purposes of use indicated to you, Olympus may forward information provided by you to Olympus' group companies, outsourcers and/or agents having confidential obligation agreement with Olympus and/or Olympus' group companies, so that such parties may directly respond to your inquiries or requests for updates, announcements regarding Olympus' products, programs, and promotions, or advertising information.

 **2\. Disclosing, Amending, or Deleting Personal Information**

You may, under the Japanese Personal Information Protection Law, request Olympus Group Companies in Japan (except for companies with their own privacy policies in place) that the personal information you provided to them be disclosed, amended or deleted.  
Please go to the Personal Information Inquiry page for more details.

 **3\. SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)**

The Websites are adopting SSL encryption technology on the pages where personal data is input so that personal data input by customers is securely exchanged.  SSL is a protocol for encrypting valuable information such as personal data which is exchanged on the Internet.  SSL can protect against the intercepting and falsifying of data, and masquerading by third parties.

 **4\. Cookies**

You can learn more about how Olympus uses cookies, and how you can restrict their use, by reviewing our Cookie Policy. 

 **5\. People under 16 years of age**

If you are under the age of 16, please make sure to obtain the consent of your parent or guardian before providing your personal information.

 **6\. Management of Personal Information**

Your personal information will be submitted to the dedicated servers managed by Olympus or its outsourcers （Olympus group companies, and/or distributors, agents of Olympus, with whom Olympus has concluded confidentiality agreements） located in the United States and the Czech Republic and will be used and shared with Olympus, its affiliates and their distributors in your country of residence or any other country outside of your country of residence (including outside the European Economic Area) in a manner consistent with Olympus Personal Information Protection Policy. 

##  **Privacy Notice ~ European Union**

The personal data collected during your visit to our website will be processed based on legal provisions effective in the country where the website is operated and managed. This privacy notice only applies when we process personal data of users who are in the European Union.  This privacy notice provides users with transparent information about how their personal data is processed, a k

The privacy and security of your personal data is very important to us. The purpose of this Privacy Notice is to transparently provide you with information about:

Who is processing your personal data  
The legal grounds for processing your data  
Why processing your personal data is important for us  
What kind of personal data we process  
When we process your personal data and  
Your rights concerning the processing of your personal data

Please read this Privacy Notice carefully. Olympus may also use cookies on its websites. For more information about the use of cookies on our websites, please see our Cookie Policy

 **1.          Contact Details  
1.1       Controller**  
Please contact our controller(s) using the following details:

Olympus Corporation

Shinjuku Monolith, 3-1 Nishi-Shinjuku 2-chome, Shinjuku-ku

Tokyo 163-0914,

Japan

Phone:+81 3 3340 2111

(in the following „Olympus“, „we“, „us“)

 **1.2        Representative of Controller or Processor**  
Please contact our representative in the union as follows:

Olympus Europa SE & Co. KG

Amsinckstrasse 63

20097 Hamburg

Germany

Phone: +49 40 23773-0

Fax: +49 40 233765

 (in the following „OEKG“).

 **1.3        Representative of Controller or Processor**

Please contact our representative in the Americas as follows:

Olympus America Inc.

3500 Corporate Parkway

Center Valley, PA 18034

United States

Phone: (484) 896-5000

Email: OCADataPrivacy@olympus.com

 **2.          General Information about the Processing of Your Data**

Personal data is only collected and processed by us (1) if it is necessary to provide a functional and convenient website and/or (2) to provide you with information about our contents, products, and services. We process your personal data only and insofar as it is permitted by national and European legal regulations. Your personal data will be stored until the purpose of storage no longer applies. In some cases, European or national regulations, laws or other regulations or contracts to which we are subject prescribe a longer or shorter storage period. Once the personal data is no longer needed to fulfill any of the identified purposes within this notice, Olympus will delete the personal data. Further details about this process can be found below.

 **3.          Processing of Your Data  
3.1       Visiting our Websites and the Creation of Logfiles**

Every time you visit our website, our system automatically collects data and information from your computer system. We collect the following data:

IP address  
Browser type/version  
Device  
Operating system  
Date and time of access  
Country  
City  
Language

This data is also stored in the log files of our system. Olympus will not store or link any of the above data to the personal data you submit through this website. It is necessary to temporarily store your IP address so that the website can be delivered to your computer. Your IP address must remain stored for the duration of your use of the website. The storage in log files therefore supports the functionality of the website. We also use this data to optimize our website and improve the security of our information technology systems. The data will not be used for marketing purposes in this context. The legal ground for the temporary storage of data and log files is Article 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

The data is stored as long as it is necessary to achieve the purpose for its collection. If data is required for the functionality of the website, this data will be deleted after the respective session has ended. The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of data in log files is absolutely necessary for the operation of the website.

 **3.2        Software Download**  
To download software on our websites, you have to fill in certain data in an input mask. The inserted data is transmitted to us and stored by us. The data will not be passed on to third parties. The following data is collected during the registration process:

Location  
Company Name  
First Name  
Last Name  
E-mail  
Phone Number  
Zip  
Username  
Password

Before completion of the registration, we ask you to consent to the processing of your data by Olympus and link to this privacy notice. If you give your consent, the legal basis for processing the data is Article 6 para. 1 a) GDPR. The data will not be passed on to third parties in this respect

Your data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.

You can revoke your consent to the processing of personal data at any time. If you contact us by contact form,  you can object to the storage of your personal data at any time.

 **3.3        Contacting us through Contact Form**

If you contact us through our contact form, the personal data transmitted with the data you filled in the contact form will be stored. Regarding the contact form we process the following data:

-        Location

-        Company Name

-        First Name

-        Last Name

-        E-mail

-        Phone Number

-        City(voluntary)

-        Zip

-        Message(voluntary)

For this processing of data, we ask for your consent prior to your submission of the data to us and refer to this privacy policy by implementing a hyperlink directly to it. The legal basis for data processing in this respect is Art. 6 para. 1 lit a GDPR. The processing of other data (e.g. connection data) during the sending process should prevent misuse of the contact form and support the security of our information technology systems. The legal basis in this respect is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

The data you filled in the contact form will be passed on to Olympus group companies or distributers inside of the EEA so that they can appropriately respond to your inquiries. 

We delete your data as soon as it is no longer necessary to achieve the purpose for which it was collected. This case occurs, if the respective correspondence with you is terminated. Correspondence is terminated when it is obvious that the questions/reasons for sending the message have been finally clarified.

You can revoke your consent to the processing of personal data at any time. If you contact us by contact form,  you can object to the storage of your personal data at any time.

 **3.4        Newsletter-Subscription**

If you have provided your consent, we will subscribe you to our Newsletter.  Once subscribed, we will inform you about interesting offers related to our products and/or services. In addition, by consenting to the subscription, you agree to receive promotional e-mails from Olympus Group Entities for certain goods and services.

We use a double-opt-in procedure if you want to register for our newsletter. This means that after you submit your registration information, we will send an e-mail to the provided e-mail address.  The email will ask you to confirm that you wish to receive the Newsletter and promotional emails.We store your IP address and date of registration and confirmation. The purpose of this procedure is to prove your registration and, if necessary, to clarify a possible misuse of your personal data.

The following data is collected during the registration process:

Location  
Company Name  
First Name  
Last Name  
E-mail

After your confirmation we will save the aforementioned data  for the purpose of sending you the newsletter and promotional emails. The legal ground for processing data in this regard is Article 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. Furthermore, processing your data is required for pre-contractual obligations, hence Article 6 para. 1 b) and f) GDPR serve as an additional legal basis because the processing of your data is necessary to provide you with the Newsletter and promotional emails.

You can revoke your consent to receive the newsletter at any time and unsubscribe from the newsletter. You can declare your revocation by clicking on the link provided in each newsletter e-mail.

Please note that Olympus evaluates your user behaviour when sending the newsletter. For this evaluation, the e-mails sent contain web beacons or tracking pixels, which represent one-pixel image files stored on our website. For the evaluations we link the data that we processed and the web beacons with your e-mail address and an individual ID.  Links received in the newsletter also contain this ID.The data is only collected pseudonymously, the IDs are not linked to your other personal data, a direct personal relationship is excluded.

We record if and when you read our newsletters, which links you clicked and deduce your personal interests from these information. The data will be processed by our contractual service partner (for further information about service partners please see below). We link this data to actions taken by you on our website.

The information is stored as long as you stay subscribed to the newsletter. After an unsubscription, we store the data purely statistically and anonymously.  Please note, that your withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

 **4.          Transfer of Personal Data to Third Countries**

If you are visiting the website from outside of the United States, please be aware that you are sending information (including personal data) to the United States where our servers are located.  That information may be transferred within the United States or back out of the United States to other countries outside of your country of residence.  These countries (including the United States) may not necessarily have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in the country of your residence, however, our collection, storage and use of your personal data will at all times continue to be governed by this privacy notice.  The following table explains which services are assigned to these companies, where they are based and which legal requirements allow us to assign these companies with the processing of your data: All internal Olympus group transfers of personal data shall be subject to written agreements which are based on Standard Contractual Clauses recognized by the European Data Protection Authority. 

Process 

Third Party 

Third Country 

Legal Grounds 

Hosting service 

Olympus Scientific Solutions Americas Corp.

Aspire

USA 

Explicit consent, Art. 49 GDPR

 **5.          Your Rights**

We want to inform you about your rights concerning the processing of your personal data by us. If you have any questions concerning your rights or if you want to exercise one or several of your rights please contact us through Contact Form.

 **5.1        Right to withdraw the data protection declaration of consent (Article 7 para. 3 GDPR)**

If the processing of your data by us is based on your explicit consent, you have the right to withdraw this consent at any time. The withdrawal of consent shall not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until withdrawal. You will be informed about this right before you give your consent.

 **5.2        Right to information (Article 15 GDPR)**

You have the right to request access to the information we have on you.  You can do this by contacting us at (insert contact form).  We will make sure to provide you with a copy of the data we process about you.  In order to comply with your request, we may ask you to verify your identify.  We will fulfill your request by sending your copy electronically, unless the request expressly specifies a different method.  For any subsequent access requests, we may charge you with an administrative fee. 

 **5.3        Right to correction (Article 16 GDPR)**

If you believe that the information we have about you is incorrect, you are welcome to contact us so we can update it and keep your data accurate.  We will correct the information without delay.  Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you also have the right to request the completion of incomplete personal data - also by means of a supplementary declaration.

 **5.4        Right to cancellation or "right to be forgotten" (Article 17 GDPR)**

You have the right to request the immediate deletion of your data if one of the following reasons applies:

  * data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed, 
  * you withdraw your consent on which the processing was based and there is no other legal basis for the processing, 
  * you oppose to the processing pursuant to Article 21 para. 1 GDPR for reasons arising from your particular situation and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for processing, 
  * you oppose to the processing for direct marketing in accordance with Article 21 para. 2 GDPR, 
  * the data has been processed unlawfully, 
  * the deletion of data is necessary to fulfil a legal obligation under European or national law, 
  * the data were collected in relation to an offer of information society services directly to a child provided in accordance with Article 8 para. 1 GDPR. 

We will comply with the request for deletion, unless we are legally obliged or entitled to continue storing and processing your data. In particular, legal retention periods are considered as legal obligations. Furthermore, we are entitled to continued storage if we are unable to assert, exercise or defend legal claims without your data. 

If we have made your data public and are obliged to delete it, we will take appropriate measures, taking into account the available technology and the implementation costs, to inform those responsible if you have also requested the deletion from them.

 **5.5        Right to ****limitation** **of processing (Article 18 GDPR)**

In accordance with Article 18 GDPR, we may only process data to a limited extent in the following cases:

you dispute the accuracy of your data until we are able to verify its accuracy,  
the processing is unlawful and you refuse to delete your data and instead request that the use of personal data be restricted,  
we no longer need the data for the purposes of processing, but you do need them to assert, exercise or defend legal claims, or  
you object to the processing pursuant to Article 21 para. 1 GDPR for reasons arising from your particular situation, as long as it is not yet clear whether the legitimate reasons for the processing by us outweigh your interests.

If processing has been restricted, we may only store this data. Any further processing in such case is only permissible with your consent or for the purpose of asserting, exercising or defending legal claims or protecting the rights of another natural or legal person or on grounds of an important public interest of the Union or a Member State. You can revoke your consent given in this connection at any time. You will be notified by us before the restriction is lifted.

 **5.6        Notification Obligation regarding Rectification or Erasure of Personal Data (Article 19 GDPR)**

We are obliged to inform all recipients to whom your data have been disclosed about a correction or deletion of your data or a restriction of the processing. This shall not apply if it is impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. We will inform you about these recipients if you so request.

 **5.7        Right to data transferability (Article 20 GDPR)**

You have the right to receive the data concerning you that you have provided to us in a structured, common and machine-readable format. You also have the right to instruct us with the transmission of your data to a third party, provided that

the processing of the data is based on your consent or on a contract and  
the processing is carried out using automated methods.

You may request that we transfer your data directly to the third party if this is technically feasible.

However, this right must not impair the rights and freedoms of other persons, including our company. If this is the case, we are entitled to refuse the surrender or transfer of your data.

 **5.8        Automated Decision in Individual Cases including Profiling (Article 22 GDPR)**

On our websites, your data is not subject of decisions made exclusively on the basis of automated processing (e.g. profiling). You have the right not to be subject to a decision based exclusively on automated processing - including profiling - if this has legal effect against you or significantly impairs it in a similar manner.

 **5.9        Right to Object (Article 21 GDPR)**

If we process your data on the basis of a legitimate interest (Article 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR), you have the right to object to this if the reasons for this arise from your particular situation. This also applies to profiling based on these provisions.

In this case, we will no longer process your data unless we can prove compelling reasons worthy of protection for the processing. This must outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

If we process your data for direct marketing purposes, you may object to the processing of your data. This also applies to profiling insofar as it is connected with such direct advertising.

After your objection, your data will no longer be processed for these purposes.

 **5.10      Right of Appeal to a Supervisory Authority (Article 77 GDPR)**

You have the right to complain to a supervisory authority, European General Data Protection Regulation, if you consider that the processing of data concerning you is not compliant with the GDPR. Other administrative or judicial remedies that you may be entitled to remain unaffected.

 **6.          Updates to our Privacy Terms & Cookie Policy**

We reserve the right to update this privacy policy regularly if the legal, technical or economic conditions change. When we update our privacy policy, we will undertake appropriate measures to inform you as required about the importance of the changes we have made. We will obtain your consent to all important changes to the privacy policy if and to the extent to which this is required under applicable data privacy laws.

 **7.          Notice regarding Hosting**

This website is hosted by Olympus Scientific Solutions Americas, located in the United States of America.

 **Last modified:   4/3/2018**
